Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- gray suit, vest, tie, smooth medium light hair, seated with book or notes, oval eyeglasses (Item 1575)
- gray suit, vest, tie, smooth medium light hair, seated with book or notes, oval eyeglasses (Item 1576)
- double breasted suit, tie, writing at desk [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 1577)
  #1577-1580, 2214, 2990 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image
- double breasted suit, tie, with book (Item 1578)
- double breasted suit, tie, writing at desk (Item 1579)
- double breasted suit, tie, white straight hair (Item 1580)
- slick medium light hair, parted almost in the middle, bow, tie, with book [Davis, Robert H., Editor, Munsey's] (Item 1581)
  # 1581, 1991, 1992, 2981 are same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image
- round dark rimmed eyeglasses, thick medium light hair with pencil [Farrar, John (Chipman), editor, The Bookman] (Item 1582)
  #1582, 3003 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image, #1582, 1583, 1993, 2946, 2947 same subject
- round dark rimmed eyeglasses, thick medium light hair with book [Farrar, John (Chipman), editor, The Bookman] (Item 1583)
  subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image, #1582, 1583, 1993, 2946, 2947 same subject
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 1584)
  #1584-1590, 2997 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image,
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 1585)
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 1586)
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 1587)
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 1588)
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 1589)
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 1590)
- thick salt & pepper hair, tweed suit, tie, seated in front of stone wall [Anderson, Sherwood, writer] (Item 1591)
- four men reading newspaper in library or waiting room, three men in work clothes, one in top hat, tie, jacket (Item 1592)
  #1592 & 1603 look like same setting
- group of men outside of a grocery store, burlap bags of nuts or coffee beans, canned goods, onions (Item 1593)
- group of 10-15 men seated on stone steps, most in shirt sleeves and hats or caps, outside of a large stone building (Item 1594)
  #1594, 1613 same image
- one woman, three men, teachers and or students (Item 1595)
- three children outside of cabin, with pail (Item 1596)
- Dr. Jaeger examining the leg of a young girl, nurse is assisting [Jaeger, Charles H., Ulmann's husband, Physician, and Assistant Professor of Orthopaedics, Columbia], 1918 (Item 1597)
  in Jacobs book, p. 14; #1597, 1612, 1708, 2645, 2635, 2646, 2800, 2972 same subject
  The Life and Photography of Doris Ulmann (Jacobs, 2001)
- three men in work clothes, with tattered felt hat, straw hat, seated outdoors (Item 1598)
- two young men in work clothes leaning and laying on a stack of burlap bags full of potatoes, docks in background (Item 1599)
  #1599, 1630 same subject
- family: father in undershirt, pants, suspenders, mother seated in dress with apron, boy, girl in school uniform, small child; appear to seated by docks (Item 1600)
- four men seated in bales of hay near a ship (Item 1601)
- two men in work clothes, woman with round eyeglasses holding a stoneware jug, all standing or seated in doorway (Item 1602)
- two young men playing checkers, third man watching; a fourth is in background with suit, tie, hat reading newspaper (Item 1603)
  #1592 & 1603 look like same sitting
- two men playing checkers, both in suit, vest, tie, 1918 (Item 1604)
- three men playing pool or billiards, in shirts, ties, vests, 1918 (Item 1605)
  #1605, 1621 same image
- five men seated or standing around table with newspapers, some in suit and tie (Item 1606)
- two men, felt hats, work shirts, overalls or pants with suspenders, outdoors, in front of bushes (Item 1607)
- two girls in work clothes with milk and cream cans (Item 1608)
  #1608 girl on left is also subject in #1818 and #2533
- five children, barefoot, boys and girls, at a wagon with books--traveling library? (Item 1609)
- very elderly woman in bed, elderly man seated at bedside, young boy looking discomfited is seated on the bed (Item 1610)
- men seated in park, young boy hidden between two on left (Item 1611)
  #1611, 1631 same image
- Dr. Jaeger examining young girl, with nurse [Jaeger, Charles H., Ulmann's husband, Physician, and Assistant Professor of Orthopaedics, Columbia] (Item 1612)
  #1597, 1612, 1708, 2645, 2635, 2646, 2800, 2972 same subject; handwritten note on top of mat, possible DU's handwriting: "position of pattern as well as quantity or size in rectangle", maybe a note to herself for a second print
- group of 10-15 men seated on stone steps, most in shirt sleeves and hats or caps, outside of a large stone building (Item 1613)
- two young boys, one hold straw hat with two potatoes, both sitting on lap of older man with beard, mustache and straw hat (Item 1614)
- three men in shirt sleeves, felt hats, outside, seated on wall, young girl with basket (Item 1615)
- missing from box (Item 1616)
  mat and photograph are missing from box
- woman with lighter complexion in grid patterned dress with lily seated in front of darker woman (Item 1617)
- six boys outdoors seated at water pump (Item 1618)
- elderly man with long white beard, elderly woman with white blouse, eyeglasses, both seated (Item 1619)
- man, mustache, white hair, suit, ribbon bow tie, with girl who has light, short, curly hair (Item 1620)
  #1620, 2430, 2431, 2609, 2795, 2796, 2825 same subject (man)
- three men playing pool or billiards, in shirts, ties, vests, 1918 (Item 1621)
- elderly couple, man in white shirt, bow tie, holding hat; woman in white blouse, round eyeglasses, holding fabric bonnet (Item 1622)
- two older boys, one older girl, one small child in water at swimming area on lake or river, 1919 (Item 1623)
- boy (or girl?) with dark hair, in suit and striped tie, man seated in suit and tie, balding [Lewis, Sinclair] (Item 1624)
  #1624, 1725, 2332 same subject; note in Xerox file says boy (or girl?) is W.D. Thompson, cannot identify who W.E. Thompson is, i.e. a writer, actor, artist
- group of black men in church seated around pulpit, banner on pulpit says HELPLESS (?) (Item 1625)
- man and woman seated outside; man in suit, vest, tie with newspaper, woman in black dress, pearls, short curly medium dark hair, smiling [Barnes, Margaret Ayers (1886-1967)] (Item 1626)
  #926, 927, 1626,1627, 1761 same subject
- man and woman outside standing on door step; man in suit, vest, tie with newspaper handing the woman a book, woman in black dress, pearls, short curly medium dark hair, smiling, with cigarette [Barnes, Margaret Ayers (1886-1967)] (Item 1627)
- man and woman seated by lake or river; man in suit, vest, tie, medium dark straight hair; woman has dark hair, parted in middle and pulled back, with blouse or dress with large buttons, a pendant (Item 1628)
- young man and woman at truck or wagon with books (traveling library?); woman in flowered print dress and white cap, man in shirtsleeves, carrying basket (Item 1629)
- two young men in work clothes leaning and laying on a stack of burlap bags full of potatoes, docks in background (Item 1630)
  #1599, 1630 same subjects
- men seated in park, young boy hidden between two on left (Item 1631)
- couple in doorway, woman standing in polka dot skirt and blouse, eyeglasses; man seated in felt hat, striped shirt, suspenders, holding unfinished basket (Item 1632)
- four boys, in overalls, youngest standing in center (Item 1633)
  top mat missing, mounting is torn
- couple standing by grinding wheel, woman with polka dot apron, cloth bonnet; man with short white beard, work shirt, suspenders (Item 1634)
- three men, seated, squatting on porch in shirtsleeves [Niles, John Jacob (center), musician, friend, and assistant to Ulmann] (Item 1635)
- man seated on ground; two elderly women, white hair, in printed dresses, one seated on the ground, one standing with books [Niles, John Jacob (seated on right with back to camera), musician, friend, and assistant to Ulmann] (Item 1636)
- woman with head scarves, striped shawl holding book with man in overalls (Item 1637)
- couple, seated in doorway; woman in polka dot skirt, hair parted in middle and pulled back; man with white beard, hair, work shirt, suspenders (Item 1638)
- man with dark hair, salt and pepper beard, mustache, work shirt, holding shovel or rake handle (Item 1639)
  mat and backing torn
- man seated holding book, long white beard, felt hat, black jacket, white shirt (Item 1640)
- man in shirt and dark vest, felt hat, round eyeglasses standing in front of wide platform holding dried or drying filleted fish, in shipyard (Item 1641)
- striped suit, best, tie, standing at column with bust, holding a sculpting tool (?) (Item 1642)
  #1642-1645 same subject
- striped suit, best, tie, seated, holding a book (title is Century) (Item 1643)
- striped suit, best, tie, standing at column with bust, holding a sculpting tool (?) (Item 1644)
- striped suit, best, tie, seated, holding a book (title is Century) (Item 1645)
- felt hat, long white beard and sideburns, dark suit jacket and pants, seated with umbrella (Item 1646)
  mat is torn
- salt and pepper hair, short straight, mustache, beard, round eyeglasses, bow tie, knit cardigan sweater (Item 1647)
- older man seated, felt hat, striped suit, bow tie (Item 1648)
  #1648-1651 same subject
- older man seated, felt hat, striped suit, bow tie (Item 1649)
  #1648-1651same subject
- older man seated, felt hat, striped suit, bow tie (Item 1650)
- older man seated, felt hat, striped suit, bow tie (Item 1651)
- overalls, work shirt, mustache with sideburns, hat (Item 1652)
- straw hat, overalls, work shirt, mustache, beard (Item 1653)
- straw hat, dark bushy mustache, work clothes, kneeling on wood frame work with hand drill (Item 1654)
- felt hat, white shirt, suspenders, white beard and mustache, in wheel chair (Item 1655)
- blacksmith with hammer at anvil, felt hat, dirty white work shirt, suspenders (Item 1656)
- in cap, salt and pepper mustache, beard, work shirt, leaning over sink (Item 1657)
- man seated in front of bushel basket cleaning poultry, birds laying on table in background (Item 1658)
  in Ulmann's handwriting on back of mat: IV The Old Way, Doris Ulmann, 1000 Park Avenue, New York City, (Platinum)
- in patterned shirt, dark balding hair, mustache, seated (Item 1659)
  #1659, 1663 same image
- seated in straw hat, white mustache, eyeglasses, jacket, light shirt (Item 1660)
- tattered felt hat, overall, work shirt, eyeglasses, standing at door (Item 1661)
  #1661, 1662 same subject
- tattered felt hat, overall, work shirt, eyeglasses, standing (Item 1662)
- in patterned shirt, dark balding hair, mustache, seated (Item 1663)
- seated, dark shirt, dark vest, pants, white hair, with pipe (Item 1664)
- close up, felt hat, very soft focus, eyeglasses, work shirt (Item 1665)
- short white beard and mustache, eyeglasses, straight salt and pepper hair, striped jacket, work shirt, with newspaper (Item 1666)
  #1666, 1667 same subject
- short white beard and mustache, eyeglasses, straight salt and pepper hair, striped vest, work shirt (Item 1667)
- felt hat, short gray beard and sideburns, bushy mustache, overalls, striped work shirt standing in door way (Item 1668)
- younger, straw hat, seated, smiling, short stubbly beard and sideburns, mustache, eyeglasses, dark jacket, white shirt, smiling (Item 1669)
- white beard, mustache, sideburns, hat, stout, climbing ladder, burlap bag draped around body--picking fruit? (Item 1670)
- straw hat, torn shirt, "Pay Day" overalls, picking apples (Item 1671)
- seated, serious, white hair, longish beard, holding hat, white shirt (Item 1672)
- white hair, mustache, tweed jacket and vest, seated on wooden porch (Item 1673)
- seated with newspaper, thick curly hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, suspenders, work shirt (Item 1674)
- black felt hat, salt and pepper beard, mustache, seated, patch on knee of overalls (Item 1675)
- seated in field in work clothes, tattered hat, a watermelon nearby (Item 1676)
- long gray beard, straw hat, vest, with cane, seated (Item 1677)
- white long beard and sideburns, straw hat, smiling (Item 1678)
- seated, hat in hand, long white beard and sideburns, jacket without collar (Item 1679)
- seated, plaid shirt, suspenders, straw hat, neatly trimmed beard and mustache, with newspaper (Item 1680)
  #1680, 1681 same subject
- seated, plaid shirt, suspenders, straw hat, neatly trimmed beard and mustache, with newspaper (Item 1681)
- seated at barrel, piece of bread in hand, lunch basket, thermos, work clothes (Item 1682)
- seated in work clothes, scruffy mustache and untrimmed beard, scowling (Item 1683)
- standing in barn doorway, cow inside board, holding rake or shovel, wheelbarrow in foreground, in high boots, overalls, cap (Item 1684)
- in doorway, standing, light colored felt hat, bushy white beard, mustache, dark jacket (Item 1685)
- visor, plaid shirt, loading a barrel with small shiny machine parts (?) in a factory (?) (Item 1686)
- bald, dark jacket, salt and pepper mustache, beard (Item 1687)
- tweed suit, seated in studio, small mustache, thick light colored blond hair (Item 1688)
- dark, smooth hair, dark suit, collar pin (Item 1689)
- white hair, mustache, gray suit, high collar, 1919 (Item 1690)
- dark, smooth hair, double breasted suit (Item 1691)
- dark suit, smooth medium dark hair, neat mustache, dark eyes (Item 1692)
- thinning dark air, clean shaven, dark suit [Coolidge, Calvin] (Item 1693)
  subject identified on back of mat (not DU's handwriting)
- not white, not African, possibly Hispanic, dark curly hair, mustache, embroidered shirt (Item 1694)
- dark round black framed eyeglasses, smiling, balding dark hair, mustache, gray suit [Wilder, Thornton] (Item 1695)
- straight medium light hair slightly mussed, gray suit, seated (Item 1696)
- white long hair, beard, jacket without collar (Item 1697)
- wide brimmed felt hat (like a "Mountie" hat), plaid kerchief around neck, jacket and vest, looks like studio setting, 1917 (Item 1698)
  #1698, 2647, 2815, 2816 same subject
- young, short curly blonde hair, white shirtsleeves (Item 1699)
- young, short curly blonde hair, white shirtsleeves (Item 1700)
- dark thick curly hair, clean shaven, striped suit (Item 1701)
- dark curly, slightly unruly hair, dark suit (Item 1702)
- young, short curly blonde hair, white shirtsleeves (Item 1703)
- striped blouse or smock, curly dark hair (Item 1704)
- medium dark straight hair parted in middle, dark suit, with cigarette (Item 1705)
- standing, gray suit, medium light straight hair, 1918 (Item 1706)
- light curly hair, gray suit, with cigarette, round eyeglasses [Stetten, Dewitt, Surgeon, Lenox Hill Hospital], 1916 (Item 1707)
  subject identified on back of mat, not DU's handwriting
- formal portrait [Jaeger, Charles H., Ulmann's husband, Physician, and Assistant Professor of Orthopaedics, Columbia], 1919 (Item 1708)
  #1597, 1612, 1708, 2645, 2646, 2800, 2972 other images of Jaeger
- dark thick hair, parted in middle, double breasted suit, bow tie (Item 1709)
- thin white hair, suit, seated with newspaper (Item 1710)
- standing with cigarette, pin striped double breasted suit, round eyeglasses (Item 1711)
- seated, bow tie, suit, balding white hair, 1918 (Item 1712)
- seated, bald, mustache, dark suit (Item 1713)
- dark, straight hair and mustache, young, light colored double breasted suit (Item 1714)
- white hair, balding, seated, bow tie, very stern [Galsworthy, John (1867-1933) English writer] (Item 1715)
- seated in heavy overcoat with large fur collar, holding hat and cane in lap, mustache, round eyeglasses, thin balding hair, 1917 (Item 1716)
- seated outdoors, pince nez eyeglasses, white balding hair, beard, mustache, with book [Bradford, Gamaliel (1863-1932) American Biographer] (Item 1717)
  subject is in Bookman Oct. 1920
- seated at desk with pen, chin in hand, thin gray hair, 1919 (Item 1718)
- seated, heavyset, white hair, mustache (Item 1719)
- seated, dark suit, balding dark hair (Item 1720)
- thin medium dark hair, mustache [MacLean, Charles Agnew, Editor, the Popular] (Item 1721)
  #1721, 2328 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of Am. Editors", but not this image
- thin medium dark hair, parted in middle, mustache, seated at table (Item 1722)
- smiling, seated with thick book, dark hair, mustache, 1919 (Item 1723)
- white hair, mustache (Item 1724)
- seated with cigarette, bow tie [Lewis, Sinclair] (Item 1725)
  #1624, 1725, 2332 same subject
- medium dark hair, parted in middle, leaning on table or desk, with cigarette (Item 1726)
- thin medium dark hair, striped suit, dark rimmed round eyeglasses (Item 1727)
- white hair, seated, in profile, with cigar (Item 1728)
- oval eyeglasses, balding, seated with pencil (Item 1729)
- thin, smooth medium dark hair, smooth fair skin [Finemen, Irving, writer, (close friend of Ulmann and Julia Peterkin)] (Item 1730)
- smooth salt and pepper hair, heavy tweed jacket, holding pipe, with black armband (Item 1731)
- thin white hair, mustache, seated at desk (Item 1732)
- medium dark smooth hair, waxed mustache, beard (Item 1733)
- balding, round eyeglasses (Item 1734)
- bald, round eyeglasses (Item 1735)
- three women in gauzy gowns [Martha Graham Dancers] (Item 1736)
  two different images were numbered as 1736. This is one of the two, the second is filed at end of collection, #2976
- five women, dark stretch gowns [Martha Graham Dancers] (Item 1737)
- four women in dark stretch gowns, two in foreground, in light colored gowns, all on knees [Martha Graham Dancers] (Item 1738)
- man and woman, leaning on pedestal in stretchy costumes [Martha Graham Dancers] (Item 1739)
- six women in stretchy gowns, three on floor, three on feet [Martha Graham Dancers] (Item 1740)
- standing in bi-color long gown, long sleeves [Graham, Martha] (Item 1741)
- standing, in full, long gown with wide, ruffled collar, part of gown is held like a fan in her hand [Graham, Martha] (Item 1742)
- standing, in full, long gown with wide, ruffled collar, part of gown is held like a fan in her hand [Graham, Martha] (Item 1743)
- standing, in short sleeved long stretchy gown [Graham, Martha] (Item 1744)
- standing, in full, long gown with wide, ruffled collar [Graham, Martha] (Item 1745)
- standing, in full, long gown with wide, ruffled collar, holding part of gown in hand as a fan [Graham, Martha] (Item 1746)
- kneeling, in full, long gown with wide, ruffled collar [Graham, Martha] (Item 1747)
- kneeling, in full, long gown with wide, ruffled collar, holding part of gown in hand like a fan [Graham, Martha] (Item 1748)
- long sleeved, long bi-colored gown [Graham, Martha] (Item 1749)
- standing, short sleeved, long stretchy gown [Graham, Martha] (Item 1750)
- standing, in full, long gown with wide, ruffled collar [Graham, Martha] (Item 1751)
- standing in long sleeved, long light colored linen gown with frayed edges at hem and on sleeves [Graham, Martha] (Item 1752)
- seated in long stretchy gown with long sleeves and hood [Graham, Martha] (Item 1753)
- standing in long sleeved, long light colored linen gown with frayed edges at hem and on sleeves [Graham, Martha] (Item 1754)
- in long stretchy gown with short sleeves [Graham, Martha] (Item 1755)
- seated in long stretchy gown with long sleeves and hood [Graham, Martha] (Item 1756)
- crouching in long stretchy gown with long sleeves and hood [Graham, Martha] (Item 1757)
- standing in long sleeved, long light colored linen gown with frayed edges at hem and on sleeves [Graham, Martha] (Item 1758)
- salt and pepper hair, pulled back, parted in middle, light colored dress, holding straw band, in front of stone wall (Item 1759)
- a girl in plaid dress, leaning on table with bowl of apples, a geranium (Item 1760)
- in dark dress, pearls [Barnes, Margaret Ayers (1886-1967)] (Item 1761)
- soft straight, medium dark hair, flowered collar, 1919 (Item 1762)
- dark hair, in velvet gown or costume (Item 1763)
- seated, medium dark, soft hair pulled back, long sleeved gown (Item 1764)
- waved hair, velvet gown with white collar, with cigarette [Lewisohn, Mrs. Sam (Margaret Seligman)] (Item 1765)
  this image was also numbered 1764 and there was no image numbered 1765; # 768, 770-772, 790, 870, 1765, 2951 same subject
- silk crepe de chine blouse, pearls, dark waved hair, holding book (Item 1766)
- in lace trimmed gown [Gish, Lillian] (Item 1767)
- adolescent girl, in dress with plaid top, white bow with buttons, short medium dark hair, plastic headband, with book, wristwatch (Item 1768)
- girl with long dark hair, holding open book, seated, white dress (Item 1769)
- in kimono robe, dark curly short hair, bang (Item 1770)
- leaning on desk with pencil in hand, chin in other hand, salt and pepper hair pulled back (Item 1771)
- dark short hair, slicked back, at table with pen and Japanese ink (Item 1772)
- white hair, elderly, lace dress, pearls (Item 1773)
  #1773, 1774 same subject
- white hair, elderly, dark dress with embroidery, lace collar and sleeves, at table with pencil and paper (Item 1774)
- seated, long sleeved velvet gown with embroidery and beading, dark hair, stout [Hurst, Fannie, American author (1889-1968)] (Item 1775)
- dark hair and eyebrows, in short sleeved light colored blouse, seated with open book (Item 1776)
- kneeling in grass outdoors in theatrical costume, very long elegant peacock cape, feathered headdress (Item 1777)
- dark hair, ringlets, in white satin short sleeved town, long white gloves (Item 1778)
- two women, one looks like a clerk, seated at desk with papers, woman standing has dark coat, hat (Item 1779)
- large white collar, white hair, seated with book [Shaker Sister Adelaide of Mt. Lebanon, New York] (Item 1780)
  #872, 1780, 1785 same sub; on page 191, ca. 1925-26
- white hair, stout, in dark dress (Item 1781)
- white curly hair, oval eyeglasses, elderly, dark dress and jacket, white high collared blouse (Item 1782)
- seated, medium dark curly hair, short, floral print dress (Item 1783)
- adolescent girl, chin length curly dark hair, long pearls, seated (Item 1784)
- standing, large white collar, cloth bonnet [Shaker Sister Adelaide of Mt. Lebanon, New York] (Item 1785)
- seated, with open book, full white blouse with lace trim, dark skirt, salt and pepper hair pulled back, 1918 (Item 1786)
- wavy hair, medium dark, young, flowering tree in background (Item 1787)
- straight, thick dark chin length hair, seated with cigarette, kimono-style jacket (Item 1788)
- seated in dark jacket or blouse, at table with open book, pussy willow in vase (Item 1789)
- short dark hair, dress with ruffled trim, with cigarette (Item 1790)
- short straight hair, bangs, long notes, patterned woven or embroidered tunic [Forbes, Esther] (Item 1791)
- white hair, lace collar, old, knitting (Item 1792)
- short hair, a little wavy, dark dress, collar and sleeves have interesting decorative trim (Item 1793)
- in costume, headband, beaded belt, long straight dark hair (Item 1794)
- in long white gauzy gown/costume, very long straight dark hair hangs loose (Item 1795)
- very short dark hair, dark dress, square neck (Item 1796)
- very long hair, headband, dark dress, watch, seated (Item 1797)